You can analyze the market correctly,
predict the direction of the move, and
still lose the trade. Why? Because
having the direction of the market
without a clear reason when to enter
means absolutely nothing. Now, today I'm
here joined with Harley where I'm going
to educate to him exactly how to enter
the correct position. Now, Harley has a
very simple understanding of what
trading is like, like many of you guys
back at home. and he is going to be
representing you guys here today, asking
me live questions on how you can get the
proper entry so you could become a
profitable trader. And I say this very
confidently. I can assure you he's going
to ask very similar questions than what
you guys would be asking if you guys
were to be here present as well. So this
is a live class essentially. So sit
tight, get your notepads ready. I'm
going to educate you everything you need
so you understand how to enter the
correct trade. So first things first,
you don't need to predict every single
move in the market in order for you to
make money, right? You just need to know
what type of entry you're looking for
that makes sense for you. What type of
stop- loss, what type of take profit,
and simply when to stay away. The market
is almost like an ocean with an
abundance of fish. When you go out there
to go fish, you don't need to catch
every single fish for you to feed your
family. You just need one nice size
fish. This is the exact same thing. You
don't need to catch every single trade
in the market. You just need to catch
one specific trade that makes the most
sense for you. So what this does, it
eliminates the abundance of unnecessary
trades that you should be taking because
you have a very simple approach that
you're looking for and then you stick to
it. That's the most powerful [music]
thing. And if you create that foundation
from the beginning, you would be ahead
of 99% of traders [music] that overtrade
and over complicate their trade. You got
that? So understanding that we're only
looking for a very specific approach in
the markets, we need to distinguish how
we can find that approach. So the
easiest and simplest way is by step one
which is called topdown
analysis.
Analysis. Don't mind my handwriting. As
long as you're listening, you should
know, right? My handwriting is not the
best. So top down analysis. What does
that mean to you? What do you understand
from top down analysis?
>> Well, honestly, I'm not sure.
>> You have no idea what that means, right?
Not really.
>> Okay. So top down analysis is exactly
what it says. It's you're analyzing the
markets from top down. So the market is
divided by multiple different time
frames. So you have one the weekly time
frame,
two you have the daily time frame, you
have the 4our time frame,
you have the twohour time frame, the one
hour time frame, 30 minute time frame,
and the 15minut time frame. Now these
are the time frames that we are going to
use in order to understand if this trade
makes sense for us to enter or not. Now
there is dozens of different time
frames. You have the monthly, the
yearly, the 10-year, you have the five
minute time frame, you have the one
minute time frame, you have the 30
secondond time frame. Now what does it
mean all these different time frames?
What it means is that every single
candlestick closes every single duration
of these candlesticks. So you know what
a candlestick is, right?
>> Yeah. Like open, close down.
>> Correct. Correct. So this is a
candlestick right here. This is the wick
up, wick down. So the weekly time frame
means that every single one of these
candlesticks take a week to form. On the
daily time frame, it means that it takes
24 hours to form. On the 4 hour, it
takes four hours to form. So every
single time frame whenever you see a
candlestick it takes 4 hour for it to
open and close like you just said
>> and then obviously every single time
frame down.
>> So something that takes a week to open
and close would be a lot stronger than
something that takes 15 minutes for sure
>> because the amounts of times that this
happens is a lot less than this. and in
in seven days you'll have probably a
couple thousand 15 minute candlesticks
that close throughout the duration of
the week. So the way top down analysis
works is you start to identify the
market from the top down. Let me give
you a representation of what that looks
like. So the market is divided
by four sectors when it comes to top
down analysis. So we're going to put
here
four. So you have one which is the
weekly time frame,
two which is the daily time frame, three
is the 4 hour
and then four is going to be what we
call LT. Can you guess what that is?
>> That's you can't guess.
>> Lower time frame.
>> Yes, correct. Lower time frame. So, LT
equals lower time frames, which the
lower time frames is the 2 hour, 1 hour,
30 minute, and 15 minute. So, we've
bundled all of these time frames into
one sector, right? So, the way the top
down analysis works is you have to start
exactly what I said earlier. You analyze
from top down. So you start from the top
and then you work your way down to the
lower time frames, right? So for this
example, we're going to use this market
and we're going to set a representation
like this. This is the weekly time
frame. This market is creating this
market structure. That's what it looks
like on the weekly. On the daily,
picture as if you were to zoom in to
this market price right here, as if you
were to just get a little bit closer.
It's almost like when you look at the
earth from maps and you're very zoomed
out. When you zoom more in, you start
seeing more of the streets. You start
seeing more of the roadways, start
seeing more of the lakes. Like
everything becomes more detailed. You're
looking at the exact same Earth, the
exact same country, whatever you're
looking at, but it's just more zoomed
in. So, you see more detail. Going from
the weekly to the daily is exactly that.
You just see a little bit more structure
in this market. So this is the exact
same price. So let's call this gold for
example, right? Let's call this XUSD.
So this is gold market. So gold market
right here, let's just say that this
high point is at $4,000,
right? $4,000. $4,000 is the exact same
$4,000. It's going to be on the weekly
that it's going to be on the 4 hour that
it's going to be on the 2-hour. all the
exact same price that gold is at. Right?
I don't think you can see the four right
there. Right? So, when you zoom into the
4 hour, you're going to see a lot more
structure than you see here. You're
going to see more structure that goes up
and down. And that's what the 4 hour
would look like. But gold is at the
exact same $4,000. It's the exact same
market. You're just zooming in. And
every single time you zoom in, you just
see more details. And then obviously on
the lower time frame you would have I'm
just going to go crazy here. Yeah, I'm
just going to go crazy here with the
market structure, right? It's just super
in detail. So when you go do top down
analysis, you start from the top down.
So we identify top down analysis by
highs and lows. So I'm going to draw
this right here. Do you know what a
bullish market is?
>> No certainly.
>> No.
>> Have you ever heard of bulls and bears
like Wall Street? You ever seen like the
gra? No.
>> No, I haven't. That's right. You you've
never seen the the Bears fighting the
bulls? No.
>> No, I never saw that.
>> Okay. In Wall Street, in New York, what
is there that that people go and take
the the iconic picture
>> in the New York Stock Exchange? You've
have to have seen this.
>> What? Like the Wolf of Wall Street?
>> Yeah. But what is in the New York strip
that people go take a picture at in New
York? The bull, bro.
>> The bull. Okay. The bull.
>> Bullish equals bull equals up.
Ascension. Gota. Bearish. You know what
it means?
>> I'm guessing down.
>> Correct. But is bears
which equals essentially down.
>> Okay.
>> Now for you to identify a bullish market
and a bearish market in top down
analysis is by
higher high
and higher low.
>> Right. We'll show you that right now.
Right. So higher high
and then
higher low, right? So higher high,
higher low. And for a bearish market,
what do you think it consists of?
>> Lower low.
>> Yes. All right. That's pretty good. So
it's consisted of lower low and lower
high. Right. So for here lower
low
high.
So whenever you have a bullish market
you have higher highs and higher lows.
Whenever you have a bearish market you
have a lower low and lower high. It is
impossible. I'm going to write this
here.
This is key right here. This is a very
big important star. It is impossible
to have
a bearish
and bullish
market
at the same time.
Meaning you cannot have a lower low and
a lower high. I'm sorry, a lower low and
a higher high. You cannot have a higher
low and a lower high. You can't have a
lower high and higher low. You can't
have like there is no crossover in
between. If you have a bullish market,
it is only these. If you have a bearish
market, it's only these.
>> Why is that?
>> That'll make sense in just a second
right now. Which that is actually the
perfect question you should be asking
right now, right? Why is that? Well,
because when a market is bullish, it's
only bullish. When a market is bearish,
it's only bearish. People mistakenly do
a top-down analysis because they can't
distinguish correctly what is the
difference between a bullish and a
bearish market. Imagine if you weren't
you weren't able to predict that the
market is heading to the upside
correctly and you mistakenly identify it
as bearish and you're actually selling a
market because you identified it bearish
incorrectly when the actual top down
analysis says it's bullish. You won't
know why you're losing the trade. So
you're already starting off the first
step wrong. Like we're not even at the
entry in the position. We're just
understanding the direction of the
market. So right now the f the clearest
way to identify highs and lows in the
market is by higher high and higher low.
This market right here this is an
example that is a bullish market. Why?
Because we have higher high and higher
lows. This is a higher high and this is
a higher low. As long as market
structure is in between this higher high
and higher low, we are bullish. Imagine
this were to be an invisible line that
were to be at the highest point. This is
an invisible line that were to be at the
highest previous low point. [music] Now,
the moment this market breaks above the
last point, what do we have?
>> A higher high.
>> A new higher high. So, if we have a new
higher high, what do we have?
>> What?
>> A higher a higher low.
>> You have to have a new higher low.
Correct. So, then this would turn into
the higher low. So whenever you have a
market that goes bullish or bearish,
it's always going to create a new high
and a low. So that's the same thing just
downwards.
>> Correct? Yeah. If you were to do a
bearish example, so this were to be a
bearish example. [music] This is a lower
low right here. This is a lower high
right here. Many mistake the lower
[music] high for this point right here,
for this point right here. And the
easiest way to determine which one is
the correct lower high or last structure
point is picture this that if it were to
be the head of a snake, right? This is
the head of a snake. That's the tongue
right there.
>> The snake whenever it turns somewhere
drastic, it does a drastic turn and it's
very predictable, right? Because if not
a snake just you'll just see it slither
on like that. But whenever it wants to
change direction, it'll make a drastic
turn. The market is essentially a snake
that's trying to take the money out of
your pocket. So you want to be able to
predict these. Whoops. So this right
here is the body of the snake. Just
slang. As soon as you see the snake
turn, that is the lower high structure
point. Wherever you see that shift. So
many people when they would go identify
a market structure point, they would get
confused, right? They would, let's say
they identify a market like this. They'd
be right about the higher high, but what
they put wrong is they be like, "Oh,
this is the higher low."
Well, if you were to do the snake trick,
the head of the snake and then you work
the wa the body back and it turns, you
would realize that that is the higher
low and that is the higher high. Gotcha.
Got it? So remember the very key point
to take away from this is as long as we
are inside of
this invisible higher high and this
visible higher low, we are bullish. This
market could create a thousand moves
like this. We are still bullish.
>> Okay.
>> The moment we body candlestickly close
below that line, what happens?
>> Then you go to the lower low lower high.
>> Correct? You the market shifts to
turning bearish. Correct.
>> So now if this market shifts to bearish,
this turns to be the lower low and then
this turns to be the lower high. Same
thing. This market could stay within
this market structure forever. How long?
The moment we body candlestick below,
this turns into the lower low that turns
into the lower high. So, I'm guessing
this is like the weekly and that's the
daily.
>> No, no, no. All this would be That's a
That's a good question. This is all the
same time frame. So, right now, can you
guess what time frame that is?
>> 4 hour.
>> Impossible to tell.
>> There's there's no way.
>> That's insane. So, but why is this one
so much bigger than this?
>> Oh, it's just because the market moved
more there.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, but like you can't look at a chart
and when you look at a chart, you see
>> Yeah. Like you when you look at the
entire chart, you're only looking at one
entire time frame. You can't see the
same chart and see the weekly, daily,
and 4 hour at the same time. It It's
like if you're changing the page
essentially. So all of this is just one
time frame. And if I were to just show
you a market structure like that, you'd
never be able to tell on what type of
time frame it'd be, right? So this goes,
you know, that's a that's another great
point I was going to add. Right now,
this this market structure core applies
to all time frames. So this applies to
the weekly. This applies to the daily to
the 4 hour to the 15 minute to the 15th
second. As long as you are in between
this high point and this low point, you
are bullish. The moment you close above,
you now have a new higher high, new
higher low. The moment we close below,
new lower low, new lower high.
>> Okay. Okay,
>> you got it. We're going to
>> Okay. So I want you to identify on this
market right here the higher high and
the higher low.
This is the higher high, the higher low.
No,
you this is where price is right now.
>> That is the highest point that the price
is right now. You did it backwards. The
higher high and the higher low is this.
This is the higher high. This is the
higher low.
>> Okay.
>> Why Why did you think that that was the
higher high?
>> So, I'm guessing that's the higher high
for
>> that. That was the last higher high.
Correct. But why did you not take into
fact the current price? You're looking
to enter the remember the position the
trade is up here.
>> You can't enter a position over here.
You're right
>> that you're going into the past. That
happened two months ago. So the higher
high and the higher low is always to the
most [music] recent price action that is
happening. So identify it over here.
Where's the higher high and where's the
higher low?
Correct. Why?
>> Because that's the most recent.
>> Uh-huh. And why did you put that as the
higher low? cuz that's the last time
they changed
>> because of the snake trick.
>> Correct. Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, if you were to get the head of
the snake right here and then you were
to work your way back, that's where the
snake turns.
>> Go on.
>> Show me the higher high and higher low
over here.
>> Correct. So, that right [music] there is
the higher high and that's the higher
low. Yeah.
>> Now, show me the higher high and higher
low on the 15-minut time frame. It's
kind of difficult to tell there.
No, that's too tight. That's too tight.
I would probably say that that's the
higher low right there, but sure. Right.
So we have just done our top down
analysis on this position.
>> And what have we just identified? Is
this bullish or bearish?
>> That is bullish.
>> Correct. So weekly we're going to give
it the B of bullish.
Daily bullish or bearish?
>> Bullish.
>> Correct. So daily is bullish. 4our.
Bullish or bearish?
>> Bullish.
>> Okay.
Lower time frames. bullish or bearish
>> looks bullish to me.
>> Okay. Now, what do you think it makes
more sense to buy or to sell?
>> To buy
>> obviously, right? Because your top down
analysis tells you that the majority of
the time frames are headed
>> to the upside versus to the downside.
Now, all you have to do is find a reason
why you should buy. That's it. So,
you've just eliminated 50% of the work.
Remember, you're either clicking the buy
button, there's a buy button, and then
there's literally a sell button. You've
just eliminated the other half, right?
So, that just made your job a lot
easier, right? All you're looking now is
for reasons to enter a buy position. And
that's where we go to step two. Do you
have any questions at this point right
now before we move on to the next point?
>> No. Right now, I understand it. But when
you're saying like in the tighter ends
>> Mhm.
>> like for example here, you put like
smaller ups and downs here.
>> Okay. That's still in one.
>> Correct. High, higher, low.
>> Correct. Yeah. Every time frame is going
to distribute the highs and the lows
differently.
>> The higher the time frames typically
are, the cleaner ones. The lower the
time frames typically are the less
cleaner because there's just more
structure created more frequently. But
yes, it the same principle applies. The
way you were to tie your shoes if they
were to be Nike, Adidas, uh, Vans,
what's another true brand? Uh,
>> Jordan.
>> Jordans. Under Armour, it's the same way
you're going to tie for any shoe. If you
have a small shoe size, you have a big
shoe size, you tie your shoes the same
way. So, you identify the market
structure the same way on every single
time frame.
Any other questions? Any other concerns
at this specific point?
>> No sir.
>> Do you understand that it's impossible
to have a bearish and bullish market at
the same time? Either one mark like this
market could be bullish and then this
market could be bearish. Correct. For
example, you know, this could be bearish
if the market structure would say that.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you got that.
>> You understand highs and lows. You
understand that as soon as we
candlestick close below the higher low,
the market shifts to bearish. You got
all that.
>> So, question. If you zoom in on weekly
>> and then it becomes bearish.
>> Mhm.
>> What does that mean?
>> Well, if the weekly is bearish, more
than likely all the other time frames
will probably be one.
>> Correct. [music] Correct. So if I shrink
it down from daily to 4 hour that means
the day will be bearish.
>> It depends. The market structure can
always shift.
>> Okay.
>> It always depends. All right. So now
understanding top down analysis we're
going to move on to the next most
important thing that 99% of traders get
incorrect. Can you take a guess what it
is?
Take a guess. Let me think. Think. 99%
of traders get the next thing incorrect.
Can I get a clue?
If I give you a clue, I basically give
you it.
>> When to take the trade,
>> you know, that's pretty close. That's
not that far off. It's instead of when
to take in a trade, it's where to take a
trade, right? So, second is going to be
what is called a oi. You ever heard me
say this before?
>> I've heard it before.
>> What is this? Take a guess.
I'm brain farting but I know what it is.
Once you say it I'll understand it.
>> So it's this is called area
>> of interest.
>> Correct. Area of inest.
Area of interest is equivalent to
support and resistance.
Support and resistance.
It's equivalent to supply and demand.
It's equivalent to order block.
It's equivalent to key area,
liquidity zone,
so on and so forth. Any term that it
would lead you to determine if the trade
is good to enter the position or not is
technically an area of interest. people
just as the years have gone by, they
have complicated and made this more
complicated than what it should be. And
at the end of the day, all of these say
the exact same thing where you should
either be potentially entering the
position to buy or to sell. Does that
make sense?
>> Yeah. What exactly is all of
>> what exactly is all of this? Like each
>> each one definition for each one.
>> Okay, sure.
This right here.
All right. This is obviously, do you
know what support and resistance is?
>> So right now,
>> green line and the red line
>> essentially. So right now this table is
supporting this whiteboard, right? So
this is essentially supporting us. So
this is this is the whiteboard right
here. The whiteboard is being supported
by the table. That's the table that is
supporting the whiteboard. Okay.
>> Now, let's say we were to want to get
below the table for whatever reason and
we were to go down. The bottom of the
table is going to be the resistance. And
so, it's going to push us down. So, this
is the table right here.
>> This is us going below the table.
Essentially, what support and resistance
is is literally exactly what it is.
Something that is going to support price
to head to the upside. Something that is
going to resist price and head to the
downside.
>> Okay.
>> Supply and demand is the exact same
thing.
Okay,
>> order block is the exact same thing. Key
area is the exact same thing. Liquidity
zone is the exact same thing.
>> That's how they all
>> they are all technically the exact same
thing. Just as the years have gone by,
people have given them these new
words, these new concepts, but they all
consist the exact same thing. It's the
area where you're looking to enter the
position. So, for example, let's say we
have this market right here.
>> Is this market bullish or bearish?
bullish.
>> Where's the high and where's the low?
Correct. Right now, this is the high of
the market. This is the higher low of
the market. We're going to put here a
little HH just so we remind ourselves
that that's higher high. And this is HL
so we remind ourselves that that's
higher low. Now, our job at this point,
now that we understand that this is
bullish, right? We understand that this
market's bullish. Let's just pretend
we're only trading on this time frame.
[music] And let's just call this for
example the daily time frame on gold. We
need to find an area of interest uh
support and resistance, a supply and
demand zone, an order block, key area,
liquidity zone. So we know that support
is equivalent
to buy
and we understand that resistance
is equivalent to
correct to sell.
When you are at a resistance,
price is technically heading down and
you want to resist to continue heading
to the downside. And when you want to
buy, price is heading to the upside. You
wanted to use it as support to continue
heading to the upside. Now,
an area of interest is consisted of both
of these positions of both of these
concepts. Now, what does that mean? We
need to have a minimum of three touches
for it to be considered
an area of interest. You can have two
touches that are resistance, one touch
that is support, whatever the case is.
Right? So, I'm just going to draw a
random market right here. Right?
For example, this market bullish or
bearish?
>> Bullish.
>> Where's the high? Where's the low?
Correct. Got that right. So that's the
higher high and that's the higher low.
Now we need to find an area of interest.
The area of interest is consisted of
three touches. What do I mean by three
touches? Well, we're going to get a box,
a zone, and we're going to just draw a
zone like this throughout here. For
example,
>> just draw the zone anywhere.
>> You would draw the zone anywhere in
between the higher high and the higher
low.
>> So you only look for an area. Imagine if
these lines were to just go this way for
eternity.
>> Got it?
>> So, you're going to look for higher for
an area of interest in between these two
lines. Nothing below, nothing on top.
Because think about it. If you go and
you find an area of interest below this
higher low, when the market gets there,
it would be what?
>> Resistance. It would be bearish.
>> It would be bearish. Correct. So you
could only find the entry of the
position inside of the high and the low.
So we're just going to draw this random
box here for example inside of this
higher high and higher low. Just remove
some of these dots so it's less noise.
Right? So this area of interest that
I've just drawn inside of the high and
the low has
one support,
right? You can tell the market reacted
from that point. It has one resistance.
It has one support. And we can just
count this for now as one resistance.
Now this is consisted of four touches.
[music] This is one touch right here.
This is two touches right here. This is
three touches right here. And this is
four touches right here. We have two
resistance
and we have two support.
This has more than three touches because
obviously we have 1 2 3 4. Whenever we
are above this area, we head up.
Whenever we're below this area, we head
down. Whenever we're above, we head up.
Whenever we're below, we head down.
Whenever we are above and I just did
this and yeah correct. So whenever we
are above for example here what can we
expect?
>> Yeah hopefully it goes bullish but yeah
it's going to be a
>> it's going to be support at that point.
When price Yeah. When price goes into
that area it's going to do exactly what
it did here. If you notice if I were to
just get this right here and I were to
just block out all the noise. Right. So,
for example, let's say I were to block
out all of this right here and all of
this right here, right? So, let me just
somehow block this out right here. For
example,
what looks very similar here. As you can
tell, price broke above,
>> retested, headed up. What do we have
here? Price broke above. It's on its way
to retest
>> to continues to head up. So, that the
problem nowadays is that people just
overlook all this information and they
get lost. They're not looking at it for
what is literally right in front of
them. If you look at this right here,
broke, retested, headed up, broke,
retested. It's on its way to head up.
So, whenever we are above this area, as
we've done here one time and two times,
we should head up. So, I've identified
the area of interest because it has more
than three touches. It could consist of
two supports, two resistance. It could
be three resistance, one support. It
could all be support. It could all be
resistance. As long as it has three
touches, it is an valid area of
interest.
>> I have a question. Sure.
>> So, if it goes through,
>> what does that mean?
>> It just broke that area of interest. It
didn't
>> wait for the next one.
>> Wait for the next one. Okay, that's it.
>> And within the higher high and higher
low of the daily time frame, typically
you'll have two to three areas of
interest. So you could have one also for
example let's just say form right here
right let's just put this one for
example you have
one support here
two support here and three support here.
So if price breaks through this area and
doesn't respect it we'll just make it to
this area and wait for a reaction to
head to the upside exactly how we've
done in the past.
>> Also you could have multiple.
>> Yes. Correct. You could have multiple.
Let me clean this up. It's getting a
little messy. Right. This is probably
one of the most important things when it
comes to trading and analyzing any trade
is just having your charts as clean as
possible. People love having an
abundance of lines on their charts and
they just get overwhelmed, right? So,
let's do this again.
Is this market bullish or is it bearish?
>> Looks bullish.
>> Why? Put the higher and higher or
whatever you think it Well,
this is so it's bearish.
>> Okay. Correct.
>> Because it's headed to the downside.
>> Correct. So that is what
>> the high the lower low. No, the lower
high and then like lower low.
>> No, the lower low. So I'm glad you got
this right in terms of the direction.
Right. So this is the lower low. It's
the lowest low.
>> Lower low.
>> And then this is the lower high. Right?
Now, when it comes to an area of
interest on this position, you would do
the exact same thing. You would only
look for an area of interest in between
this.
>> So, imagine there would be an invisible
line going this way.
Now, for this example, if I were to just
draw a little zone in here like this,
>> boom. What do we have?
>> So, here,
>> how many taps does this area of interest
have? Yeah.
>> Three.
>> Drama.
Eight.
Yeah.
>> Okay. Out of how how many supports and
how many resistance is this area of
interest consisted of?
>> This is a support
a resistance and support.
>> Correct. So this is technically
consisted of one support,
two resistance and three support. That
is a valid area of interest. Now what we
need to do as traders, we need to wait
for price to simply come back into this
area of interest and then we'll look for
our reason to enter the position. But
our area of interest tells us where we
enter the trade. Remember how earlier I
asked you what's the second step? You
said when to enter the position. No,
it's where. So we can be right about the
direction, but now we know exactly when
or where we would be interested on
clicking that sell button in this
example. Now, if you don't have a and
this is very key, right? I'm gonna draw
another key point right here. Now, this
is a major key.
And I'm gonna do a really big star for
this one.
No three touches.
No area of interest.
>> If it doesn't touch three times,
>> if the area of if there's no three
touches, there is no area of interest.
Wait,
>> find me the area of interest of that
position.
>> There's no area of interest.
>> Correct. If you were to simply draw the
dotted line this way,
draw it this way. Here you have one tap
here. This is another area of interest.
You have one tap and there's nothing
else. So there's no three touches, no
area of interest. And that's perfectly
fine. And this is why you would just
simply move on to the next trick. This
is why there's dozens of different
markets that you can trade. There's
dozens of different opportunities in the
market.
No three touches, no area of interest.
Any questions at this point?
>> Oh, sorry.
>> Makes a lot of sense. Am I a really good
teacher or you just don't?
>> No, you're a good teacher.
>> You sure?
>> I'm learning a lot more today than I've
learned ever. [laughter]
>> Okay. So, for example, let's say this
market right here.
Bullish or bearish?
>> Bullish. Put the high and put the low.
Okay. What's the next step? Step two is
what?
>> Correct. Correct. The invisible lines.
>> Now, the block.
>> Correct.
>> Is that a valid area of interest?
>> No.
>> Why?
Because well it has three touches but
that means it's
>> No, that's it. It has three touches.
What does that say here?
>> Yeah, three touches.
>> Three touches is all you need. So one,
two, and three. Correct. It all three of
them could be resistance. All three of
them could be support. They could be a
dynamic of them back and forth. What we
would wait for now is for this price to
come back into this area, give us a
reaction, and then we enter the trade to
the upside.
>> Cool.
>> Easy. Simple.
>> Yeah. Now area of interest is extremely
key to looking to enter a position.
Sometimes you can have multiple
different areas of interest.
All right, let me just go like that. So
this market is bullish. So this would be
obviously higher high, higher low. Now
here you would have for example, let's
say let's say this area of interest
right here. Should have draw out that
area of interest. We have one, two,
three, four, five. Would you agree?
Yeah. Now, so you have through here,
let's just through right here. You also
have this area of interest. You have one
2 3 4. Right? So this is this is what
would be called area of interest
one, area of interest two.
Many question traders ask all the time
when they join my community and we enter
these live sessions. Which area of
interest do we enter at? Which one's
stronger? What would you say? Would it
be area of interest one?
>> Five.
>> Okay, that's a great answer. And it's
technically not incorrect. The area that
has the more taps should be the area
that it gets respected, but that's never
always the case. So, you don't ever want
to be biased to an area of interest. You
don't ever want to say, you know what, I
only trade at areas of interest ones or
I only trade at areas of interest twos.
That doesn't mean anything. And you
should also shouldn't say, I'm only
going to enter the position on area of
interest one because it has more taps
than area of interest too. Whatever the
case is, right? There's so many other
things that go into the entering the
position that once price is at this area
of interest, you need to treat it as if
there is no other area of interest.
>> Okay?
>> Treat it as if that is the only area of
interest and you look for the reason to
enter the position there. If you enter
the position there and it loses and it
goes continuous down, you wait for it to
get to your second area of interest and
then you treat that as a brand new trade
as if it never reacted to the first area
of interest and you treat it uniquely.
That's ve very important that traders
understand this very early on into the
journey because it would save them so
much trauma in terms of their indecision
of which area of interest should they
always take the trade at. It's like
which one do I do? Do I do this one or
do I do this one? There's never a right
answer. What you're doing with placing
these areas of interest is you're
eliminating
all of this empty space that's up here,
all of this empty space down here, and
you're just putting two key areas for
you to interest of entering the
position. And you just have to react and
have the strategy which we're going to
break down right now at these two key
areas.
>> You understand that?
>> Make sense? Yeah.
>> Okay. Any questions at this point?
>> So to confirm, you you look at this one,
the first one.
>> Yeah. You always treat the nearest one
to price as the first area. If it breaks
that area, this area of interest
technically gets removed completely and
then you're only going to treat the
trade for this area of interest now. All
right.
>> If it has broken and and did not respect
that area.
>> Correct.
>> Now, moving on to our third point. Can
you take a guess what it's going to be?
>> Allow one to take the trade.
>> Correct. Now, what do you need in order
for you to enter the position
or what do you assume you need?
um
the right signals.
>> Correct. Not going to lie, you're a
pretty good guesser. [laughter]
A lot better than what I was. So, yes,
the third step would technically be
entry
signal. Now, what has happened
throughout the years, and I was victim
of this as well, is I would jump the gun
and just go straight to entry signal. I
assumed that in order for you to make
money in trading, you would need to
understand what is the reason why your
entry signal leads you to enter the
position. But what I didn't understand
were all the steps prior to the entry
signal. For example, what what is the
first step that you would look for?
>> Top down analysis.
>> Correct? So step one would be topdown
analysis. And what would the second step
be?
>> AOI.
>> Correct? Which would be the step that we
just went through. So, in order for you
to have the entry signal there, there's
a buildup to this entry signal. You
first need to know why you're looking to
buy or sell. The reason you do that is
by top analysis. If for example, out of
the weekly, daily, 4 hour, 2our, and 1
hour, let's say the weekly is bullish,
daily is bullish, 4 hour is bearish, 2
hour is bearish, and then the 1 hour is
bullish.
Out of all of these six time frames, I'm
sorry, five time frames, you have
one, two points that lead you to sell.
One, two, and three that lead you to
buy. Now, obviously, what has the
majority of the time frames going up is
going to win. But the weekly and the
daily alone are far stronger than all
three of these time frames. So, even if
this were to be bearish, let's just say
that this were to be bearish.
Oh, wrong marker. Let's say that this
were to be bearish,
this would still be stronger of a reason
to buy than to sell because you would be
buying with the higher time frames and
then you can also be selling with the
lower time frames. Now, this is all a
little bit more complex of a strategy
and I can teach you this at a different
time when I'm teaching you the core
basis of entering a position. But the
point is let's say you're looking to buy
with the higher time frames or sell with
the lower time frames. You understand
that because of
>> top down analysis
>> correct? So understanding top down
analysis then you would have the area
where you're looking to enter the
position which you already know that the
area to enter the position needs to be a
key area. An area that has been
respected in the past. Whenever you're
above, whenever you're below, whenever
you're above and price is coming back,
you can expect for it to have a push to
the upside. Now, when you're inside of
this area of interest, and this is a key
thing that I actually forgot to add in
the area of interest, you can only
write this down, guys. If you guys are
at home, bring out your notepads. And if
you aren't subscribed to the channel,
subscribe at this very moment right now.
Hit that like and thumbs up. We love
that. You can only have
the
entry signal.
Actually, we'll say like this. You can
only
move on to the next step. You can only
move to step three when
you are
inside
the AOI. So for example, let's say this
market right here, right? This is our
AOI. This market whenever we're below
rejects. Whenever we're above, we're
rejects.
Now this can you go to the third step of
the entry signal? Yes or no? No sir.
>> Why
>> doesn't have three?
>> Actually a trick question and you got it
right.
>> Okay.
>> You scared me.
>> What about now? Can you go on to the
entry signal?
>> Yeah.
>> No.
>> You cannot move on into the entry signal
until you are not inside.
>> So this has to hit
>> correct until you're not inside. So
right now you can't even go to the third
step to the entry signal because you're
not inside of the AOI. Are you inside?
>> No.
>> That Yeah, that right there is called
And you know we could we can add this
right here as well. And you're either
inside or
you are inside
or
at the area of interest. That is
technically at the area of interest.
That right here is inside of the area of
interest. And that right there is what?
>> It's outside.
>> Outside.
>> So that right there invalidates the
trade. you cannot move on to the third
step. So you will only look for this
entry signal once you are either which
one
>> inside
>> or
at
>> on yeah
>> or on it. Correct. Either at or on the
entry signal or at or on the area of
interest. So that is a key point that's
very important. This right here would be
categorized as the trade on the way to
the area of interest. So, this is just
on the way to the area. We're expecting
for price to come here. And there's many
times where the market simply does this
and it just has to push to the upside
and it never comes to the area of
interest. That's perfectly fine. That
was never our trade in the first place.
We don't dread on those. There's nothing
that we can do about it. It's almost
like if you are
like you're a fisherman and you just
caught a decent sized fish, you're
taking it off of the hook and you see a
ginormous tuna triple the size pass
right by in front of the boat. You're
not going to jump into the water and try
and manhandle the fish, right? You just
wasn't your fish. You were focused on
something else at the time. You move on
to the next one. There will be more fish
and more opportunities. This is the
exact same thing. If price doesn't come
back into this area does not give you
your entry at this trade, you never take
the trade, right? So, very
>> question.
>> Okay.
>> So, what if it just went right through?
>> Like what if you bought like you went
into the trade there and then it just
went right through.
>> You just took a loss.
you yeah you move on to the next trade
but you try and avoid those by having
this next step which we're going to
break down right now
>> which is the entry signal because
remember great question we'll do the
same thing right same exact example
>> one two
three
and right we're at the area of interest
you don't just jump in you you don't you
know we can this could be a key point to
the entry point but you don't jump into
the position just because we're at the
area of interest. When you're at the
area of interest, that's when then you
go to the entry signal. And now is
technically where the real trading would
come into play because everything prior
to what we've been doing is just
analyzing the trade to be interested.
Now is when we actually start playing
ball. Now is when we're in the game
because now we're looking for a reason
to enter the position. All right?
>> So you don't just enter because price is
at the top or at the middle.
>> Make sense?
>> Yeah. Okay. So people will watch this
video for free.
>> Yeah, this will be on YouTube free.
>> Yeah, this is this is a good sauce for
YouTube, right?
>> So now that we understand that we could
only move on to the next step which is
the entry signal once we are at the area
of interest. Now comes the actual
playing ball, right? This is where we
actually start to look to enter a
position and this is where the
neverending options present themselves.
You know, you can go out to the deep
ocean, right? My analogies are kind of
crazy sometimes. That's not the market
structure. It works though.
>> Yeah. That's a market ocean right there.
Right. This could be you and I on our
little boat right here. Right. Do a a
little flag. This is you. And this is
me. I'm a little bit bigger than you. We
have our rods
fishing. Down here we have
tuna.
We have
pretty good shark, right?
>> You can draw two.
>> Oh, dude. That was a terrible shark. We
have a bigger shark. We have little
Oh, dude. How do I do this? Like this.
We have little Nemo. And then we have
giant squid over here. Right. When we're
fishing up there on the boat, we need to
have the appropriate bait depending on
this type of trade, right? There's
dozens of different options that we can
choose from. The exact same thing for
the entry signal. There's dozens of
different types of entry signals that
you can have, but we will only be
trading one type of entry signal. We
will only be looking to fish for one
type of fish. We're going to be the best
possible fisherman for
tuna, right? We're going to only be
looking to enter off of
conformation
entries
only. What does that lead you to
understand? What is a confiration entry?
Let me actually write that again. What
do you understand by that?
>> From the words, I'm guessing it'll be
like something that was already like
accumulated [music] like that you put
together.
>> Something that has already happened is
essentially what it is. A confirmation
entry is something that has already
happened. People have a lot of
anticipation candlesticks which is the
most degenerate way of trading in my
opinion and it's what leads to having
the least amount of success in trading
because people anticipate too much.
Anticipation
entry, right? So anticipation is
waiting.
I'm sorry. Anticipation is essentially
no waiting.
And then the confirmation is waiting.
Here you don't wait for a candlestick to
close. Don't wait for a candle closure
or candle closure. And when you wait,
when you're waiting, you wait
for a candle closure,
>> closure.
>> So you wait for the candle to form.
>> Correct. You wait for the candlestick to
open and to close. A lot of people, they
don't. They as soon as a candlestick
opens and it's creating something, they
just enter right away. That's the
anticipation because they're
anticipating that it can go in their
direction. It's essentially like if you
were to throw out your rod with the bait
and you see the fish looking to nibble
it and you just yank up
>> and then do you catch the fish?
>> No.
>> Sometimes
>> sometimes it but it's very rare. So
that's exactly what trading off of an
anticipation entry is that you basically
are anticipating for that candlestick to
go in that direction but there's no
confirmation because a candlestick
hasn't closed.
>> So a confirmation candlestick is when a
candlestick closes. Now there's multiple
different entry signals that we look to
have in a position. We can look to have
confirmation candlesticks such as a
bullish and bearish engulfing
candlestick. So we know the market
consists of candlesticks like this.
Right?
Now this is what a bullish candlestick
would consist of. Very simple bullish
engulfing candlestick.
Bullish engulfing candlestick is
literally what it means. When something
engulfs something, it means that it has
eaten the candlestick to the left. So,
this is what a bullish engulfing
candlestick would look like and would be
one of our entry signals off of a
confirmation. We would need to wait for
this candlestick to close and then the
next one open. So, the next one would
open up here. Technically, we would get
a bit of a worse entry because we would
enter up here rather than if this
candlestick was forming. People that
enter off of an anticipation
candlestick, they enter all the way down
here. But the problem is that they don't
have any entry signal. They're just
anticipating that that's going to be a
confirmation candle.
>> Might feel good that you could
anticipate that, but there's no real
strategy behind that. So, one of our
entry signals is the bullish engulfing
candlestick, which would essentially be
built by its cousin. its brother,
however you want to call it, which would
be the bearish engulfing candlestick,
right? The bearish engulfing candlestick
is obviously when you're looking to sell
a position and then the bullish
engulfing candlestick is when you're
looking to buy a position. Picture this
here as the area of interest. So,
picture this market as if it were to be
moving like this. And this is just the
candlestick having the retracement. This
is the area of interest. So now that
you're at the area of interest, you need
to wait for that engulfing candlestick.
[music]
Many would enter the position just like
this. Just because price [music] has
come back into the area of interest,
they would go ahead and enter the
position there. But what end up
happening is that there's no
confirmation. This candlestick would
open up, maybe create a little bit of a
wick to the upside, like it looks like
it's going to go to the upside, and
they're anticipating that that's going
to be the move.
>> [music]
>> what it ends up doing just creates the
wick and then this just ends up being
another massive candlestick here. So
people are entering off of an
anticipation rather than a confirmation.
A confirmation would be to wait for this
candlestick to close and it would lead
you to determine if that is a real
position to enter or not. So for
example, now that we're inside of this
area of interest, what we would want to
wait for is for this confirmation
candlestick. We would want to wait for
this candlestick to close with a bullish
engulfing candlestick. Now we have top
down analysis. We know that this is
bullish. We know that this is a valid
area of interest because it has three
touches. And now we have our entry
signal which this candlestick is [music]
going in the direction of the top down
analysis. You see how all this starts
coming together? How it's all painting a
picture? Makes
>> sense.
>> Do you have a question on this
specifically right now?
>> So just wait for the candlestick that
goes inside to close.
>> Correct. Okay,
>> so the entry signal is obviously the
area that needs to happen.
>> Well, what time frame do I have to look
for for the entry signal?
>> What time frame should you have the
entry signal? Great question. I was
going to go right into that right now.
>> So, your entry signal can really consist
on any time frame depending on the
position that you're taking. Obviously,
keep in mind this is the time frames
that we will be trading. Weekly, daily,
4 hour, 2 hour, and then 1 hour. We'll
just keep it there because you know that
this is the lower time frames. The
higher the time frame, the stronger the
entry signal confirmation. The lower the
time frame, the weaker. So, it would
really come down to how the trade is
presenting itself. Do you have the
weekly is bullish, the daily is bullish,
the 4 hour is bearish,
the two hour is bearish, and then the
one hour is also bullish. Are you
getting this bullish engulfing
candlestick at a weekly I'm sorry at a
daily area of interest or at a weekly
area of interest? Are you getting it on
a 4hour area of interest? It really
comes down to so many different factors,
but it if I were to just give you a
generic answer, it'd be every single
time frame qualifies for an entry
signal. So you can have this engulfing
candlestick forming at an area of
interest on any time frame. This is
almost picture as if it were like you
were to be building your own car. You
can put whatever color, whatever rim,
whatever interior. You're having the
same car be built however custom you
want. You're taking the trade however
custom you want. I would just always
look for this entry confirmation. Look
for the areas of interest. everything on
the higher end as you possibly can of
the top that analysis. But I personally
only look for areas of interest on the
weekly, daily, and 4hour. And I only
look for my entry signals on weekly, I'm
sorry, daily, 4 hour, and then lower
time frames. I just personally if I were
to have like a favorite I would have my
favorite be 4 hour and then daily. Cool.
>> So if I if I were to just narrow all
this down to the most respected entry
signals and area of interest, it would
be the 4 hour and the daily. But you can
have your entry signal technically be
formed on any time frame. Just the
higher the time frame, the more
respected.
>> Got it?
>> Got it? Now for the entry signal, the
bullish engulfing is really [music] the
simplest one and it's good that you
understand the confirmation entry
because there is dozens of difference of
entry signal confirmations which is what
I want to really double down on right
now [music] because same way how there's
an abundance amount of fish out there,
there's an abundance amount of entry
confirmations. You can have morning
star, evening star. Have you heard of
these confirmations before or no?
>> Nope.
>> No. Okay. So, one of my personal
favorite is going to be a morning star
formation. Typically, when you have a
market approach an area, you have a
small candlestick with a wick and then
you would have an engulfing candlestick
[music] that engulfves the last two
candlesticks. So, it engulfves this
smaller candlestick and it [music]
engulfves this smaller candlestick.
Remember, key point to remember here all
of these and I'm going to put this very
close to you over here so you don't
forget. Every entry signal
entry
signal
needs to be
where
in the area [music] of interest.
>> Correct. At the area of interest. No
AOI.
No
entry
price. Just to give you a very simple
example real quick, this can be bullish.
This can be the area of interest right
here. You could have the morning star
formation, the bullish engulfing present
itself not at the area of interest. Do
you take to trade yes or no?
>> No.
>> Correct. No area of interest, no entry.
Very powerful that you understand that.
The sooner you understand that, the
sooner you will start to avoid losses.
And it's very important that you
understand this. Right? Key point to
remember there. Now this is what would
be called a morning star
formation.
Morning star formation is when you have
two candlesticks that are engulfed by
one at the area of interest. Evening
star is quite the same thing. Price is
approach at this area. You have a dogee
a shooting star and then price would
have a bearish engulfing. So this is
where we anticipate for price to head to
the downside. This is where we
anticipate for price to continue heading
to the upside. Simple at that point.
>> So this is just morning star and evening
star formation.
>> So evening star is the same thing just
bearish.
>> Correct. Just the complete opposite.
Bearish. Correct. Now you have what is
called the shooting star. This is where
price approaches an area of interest.
Oh, got to do red candlesticks because
obviously if price is heading down, we
have red candlesticks.
So, we've approached an area of
interest, right? This is an area of
interest right here. And then price has
done this.
That right there is a shooting star, a
wick, a flying dogee. People give it a
bunch of different names. It's simply a
rejection. At one point, this
candlestick was entirely bearish,
meaning this candlestick was like that
at one point. And then this area of
interest, this support level was so
strong that it made price close to the
upside. and it left the wick. You know
what the wicks consist of?
>> Open and closed.
>> Yes. But the wick is almost like the
trail of where price has been in the
past.
>> Okay.
>> So market whenever a candlestick opens,
it's always going to open flat. So when
you see it flickering to the upside, it
starts creating a little move like that.
But then if it decides to continue to go
to the downside, the highest point that
it was, it stays there in representation
of a wick. So it it's like the footprint
that the market was there at one point
and for whatever reason it just closed
the other way. So this dogee, this
shooting star, so I like to call them
just dois
is one of my top three because it
clearly shows that price was trying to
break through the area and it couldn't
and price was pushed all the way back
up. The bigger the wick,
the better. The stronger the wick, the
better. If you have no wick on top, even
better because it means that price
straight tried to open and go down and
it couldn't and it was held all the way
to the upside.
>> Better to sell.
>> No, in this case, it'd be the buy
because this this is this is a
rejection. Wherever you see a wick, it
means rejection. It means price was
there at one point and then it couldn't
continue to hold. So, then it went to
the upside. Now, this is where things
start getting powerful is when you start
combining all of these different
confirmations because let's say that
this next candle, let's say you don't
want to enter just off of the dogee
alone. This next candlestick has an
engulfing candlestick. What do you have
there?
>> A morning star formation.
>> Correct? So, this is the morning star
that has just engulfed the last two
candlesticks. So, you have a morning
star, you have a bullish engulfing
candlestick, and you also have the dogee
rejection. See? So this is the dogee
candlestick rejection and you can add an
engulfing candlestick to it. Then you
have the morning star formation so on
and so forth.
>> Can you elaborate more on the wick? Like
what exactly
>> on the wick?
>> Okay. To give you a simple analogy,
let's say for example
this were to be you, right? This is you
right here.
>> Mhm.
>> And you want to go to McDonald's.
McDonald's. That's over here. Now, if
you were to go ahead and start walking
to McDonald's, you're going to leave a
footprint behind. That's one shoe.
That's your other shoe. That's your
other shoe. Now, as you're getting close
to McDonald's, you realize, you know
what? McDonald's is probably not the
healthiest option. Let me go to Wendy's.
Just slightly better of an option. So,
that's where you decide to change your
path and go this way. Now, you're
starting to go to Wendy's. As you're
getting closer to Wendy's, you realize,
you know what? I rather have
Chick-fil-A. So, this is where you would
go to Chick-fil-A. And then you would
start walking this way. Now, this is
your footprints. That shows where you
were going, where you changed to, and
then where you ended up going, and then
you walk into Chick-fil-A and you're
eating your McChick or whatever you eat
at Chick. I've actually never eaten at
Chick-fil-A ever. Never in my life.
>> Why? Cuz we went like on a Sunday.
>> No, I've just never eaten at Chick. I
just don't eat that type of food. I
don't know.
>> To me, it's fast food. Right
>> now, these footsteps represent that
that's where you were going. So people
don't have to see where you are and they
can follow the footsteps and they can
tell where you ended up. The wick is the
exact same thing. When a candlestick
opens, it's always going to open flat.
So let's say for example, this
candlestick was bullish.
This candlestick was bullish. The next
candlestick always opens where this
candlestick closed. So this candlestick
would open right there as a flat line
and then it would slowly flicker to the
upside, right? So the candlestick would
start heading to the upside. That right
there is the highest point that that
candlestick has been in the first 5
minutes. Let's say for whatever reason
price decided to not like that area and
it starts heading to the downside. It
gets smaller. As it gets smaller, it's
going to leave that wick there because
that's a bar that was raised and it was
there at one point. Now, let's say, for
example, it doesn't like that area and
then it just starts from here. It's
going to start heading to the downside.
It's going to leave a bigger wick. Now,
let's say from from here, from this
lowest point that we've been on this
candlestick here, it stops going to the
downside because buyers start coming
back into the market. It starts pushing
price up. So, it's going to do the exact
same thing. It's going to leave a wick
there to where price was at that point.
Now, let's say for example, price
decides to continue to go back up and it
starts to go back over here. That wick
is gone essentially and it's this is the
highest point that the market has been.
Now, if the market slightly starts to
get some sells into the market, that's
the highest point we've been in the
market. It's going to leave that wick.
So, essentially, the wick is where that
candlestick has been fluctuating up and
down. And that's why you always want to
enter off of a candlestick closure
because it has given you the
confirmation of what it has closed like
because on let's say this is the 1 hour
time frame at 50 minutes this can look
like this but at 60 seconds before the
candlestick closing it could be entirely
different because it's an entire hour it
can change. Does that make sense?
>> Yeah. And the the whole candlestick I'm
guessing that's the whole time frame
like that's the 4 hours
>> correct? Yes. So this one candlestick
could be four hours. So it takes four
hours for this one candlestick to close.
>> Correct.
>> Okay.
>> Any questions regarding this?
>> No sir.
>> Now that you understand the multiple
different types of entry signals, you
have dois, engulfings, moaning
sirations, you always want to wait for
the candlestick to [music] close. That
is your confirmation. Now once you have
your confirmation, do you enter the
position? Yes or no?
Yes.
>> No. Trick question and it's okay to
answer that incorrectly. Many would want
to enter a position as soon as they have
their entry confirmation and that would
actually be a major mistake because
there's multiple things they need to do
after they actually decide to enter the
position. So for example, let's set this
very simple example right here. Bullish
market, right? bullish market.
Market starts to have a little bit of a
retracement
around here.
Now, let's pretend like this is our area
of interest right here in this area. So,
now this market, would you consider this
bullish or bearish?
>> It's bullish.
>> Correct. Right. I'll make it easy for
you. Right. This market is bullish. Just
going to draw some bearish candlesticks
here just to represent that we've been
here in the past. Right? Whatever.
Right? So, this market is technically a
bullish market. Right? This is going to
be the higher high.
This is going to be the higher low. We
know that this is our area of interest
because let's just represent that there
would be three touches at this area.
Three touches. Let's just pretend that
that is done. Let's say more this way.
There's three touches. Now we have one.
Oh, that was not bad. We have one which
is what?
>> Um top down analysis.
>> Correct. So top down analysis is done.
We know that the majority of time frames
are bullish in this example. Two.
>> AI.
>> Do we have our area of interest?
>> Yes sir.
>> Now three
signal which was the confirmation and
now
>> correct.
Can we move on to step three yet?
>> No.
>> Why?
>> Because
>> because what?
>> You said that's not the only
>> No, we can't move on to step three
because we are not at our area of
interest.
>> If you look, price is not at the area of
interest. So, we can't move to our entry
signal until we're not at the area of
interest. So, as of right now, we're not
there yet. Now, this candlestick,
are we at the area of interest? Yes or
no?
>> Yes.
>> You sure?
>> Well, you're on it.
>> So, we're technically at the area of
interest. Okay. So, now we could move on
to our next step, which is going to be
our
entry signal. Now, for the third step is
our entry signal. Do you see an entry
signal?
>> Nope. I don't see a dogee. All right.
ju just because of a dogee
>> or the rising star.
>> Morning star.
>> Close enough. Right. You have access to
this recording. You can go back and
watch this forever. Right. I don't
expect you to learn all of this like
right off the bat. It's a lot of
information. Correct. You don't have an
entry signal yet. So you can't enter
this position. So as of right now, you
are still waiting for your entry signal.
You cannot enter. I mean, you could
enter off of an anticipation, but it
would be a big mistake. You want to wait
for an entry confirmation. Now, this
candlestick right here.
Is that your entry signal?
>> No. That's not a dogey or a warning
star.
>> Okay. Sure. You sure you don't want to
enter off of anticipation?
>> No, sir.
>> You sure? You'll be surprised how many
people get tempted at this point to
enter off of an anticipation them
anticipating the next candlestick. Now
you have this candlestick. Is that your
entry signal?
>> Yes.
>> You sure?
>> Yeah. It's eating those two.
>> Correct. So that is a
>> morning star formation. Now you can't
just jump into the position. You can't
literally just go and decide to enter
this buy and click the buy button.
>> You need two of the most important
things when it comes to actually trading
at this point because remember now we're
actually trading. Before what we were
doing is just determining if this is a
good trade to take or not. Okay. Now is
when actual trading comes into play.
First step, the most important step that
like from all of this is going to be
stop loss
placement. Do you know what that means?
>> No sir.
>> What is what do you think a stop loss
is?
>> Where you stop where like you can put an
indicator to stop it so you don't keep
losing more. Correct.
>> Okay.
>> A stop loss is literally it stops your
loss essentially if you're wrong. Right.
Then the next is going to be Oh, I keep
dropping these markers. Next step is
going to be your
take profit.
People love to just focus on where
they're going to place the trade when
they're going to make money. This is
where they make money. This is where
they would essentially lose money.
People don't ever focus on how much
they're going to lose because they're
just so focused on the upside gain from
this market opportunity, which is the
wrong thing to do. You always need to
preserve your capital first and then we
can talk about where you're going to
make your profits. But you always need
to place your stop-loss first. So when
it comes to entering the position, you
need to have your entry signal
confirmation and then comes the actual
trading part which your first step would
be your stop loss. Your stop loss is
going to be placed always and this is a
major key needs to be placed
at a area
where
if it gets hit
if it gets hit you are
wrong. What does that mean? Almost as if
you were to go and
fishing. Same fishing example. Pretty
good with these fishing analogies,
right? So, let's say you're going to go
out there and catch a big tuna. And the
weight of the line that you're using is
only meant for 100 pounds. That's for a
reason. Because the rod that you're
using can only really reel in a fish
that's 100 lb. If you have a line that
catches a fish that is 200 lb, for
example, so you know, if I were to just
use here the the rod example, this is
your fishing pole, but the line that
you're using is heavier than the one
that's meant for the rod. Your line
won't snap when you catch a 200lb fish,
but your rod will. Yep.
>> So, what's more valuable, the line or
the rod?
>> The rod,
>> obviously. So, what's more valuable?
one simple trade or your entire trading
account.
>> Well, the whole
>> your trading account.
>> Correct. So, you need to make sure that
you're placing the proper line that goes
in proportion with the rod so you don't
snap your rod. You need to make sure
that you're placing your stop loss at an
area where if it gets hit, you're wrong.
So, if you catch the wrong fish, the
line is telling you that you're catching
a fish that's too heavy, that is not
meant for the rod. If you place a stop
loss at an area where if it gets hit, it
tells you that you're wrong about the
trade. It tells you to go move on to
another position. So, that is major key
that 99% of traders don't do. Your stop
loss always needs to be placed ideally
for you to have the best stop-loss below
the area of interest because what
happens below the area of interest? When
price comes into this area, technically
if we're below the area of interest, we
should retest it and continue heading to
the downside. Many traders, for whatever
reason, they want to be heroes and they
want [music] to enter the position up
here and then have their stop loss be
right at the bottom of that wick or
right at the bottom of that move or up
here or up here. They always want to
have a tight stop loss. For me, I always
want to have a big stop loss because
[music] I don't want to lose a position.
And if you have a big enough stop loss
and you're right about the direction,
you probably won't ever lose. So, I like
to have my stop loss be below the area
of interest. So, if this is your entry
up here, your stop loss needs to be
below this area of interest because if
this next candlestick decides to open up
and then head to the downside, you're
technically wrong about the position as
a whole.
>> Okay.
>> How below.
>> How below. That's that's a great
question. It could be below anywhere
from five to 10 pips. Pips is point in
percentage. It's just how you measure
it. But it would be 5 to 10 pips below
that area of interest.
>> Okay,
>> does that make sense?
>> I'll learn what pips are in the future.
>> Yeah, pips is point [music] in
percentage. There's a tool on Trading
View. You just measure it very easy that
that's not a problem. So, we know that
the stop loss needs to be below that
area of interest. So, this would be
where you're entering the position up
here. Now, next step is your [music]
take profit. For me, the takerit I don't
really care about because your takerit
all that matters for it is that it needs
to be at a minimum of a one to two
risk-to-reward always. What does that
mean?
>> What does that mean?
>> One to two.
>> One to two. Great question. So, one to
two risk-to-reward is actually the
reason why traders are profitable. So
stop-loss is the reason why traders
don't blow their entire account. And
then the risk-to-reward is why traders
are actually profitable. Typically
traders, if you're a really good trader,
including myself, I probably have a 50%
win rate.
Literally, meaning out of 10 trades,
I'll lose five and I'll win five and
I'll still be profitable. You're asking
how. If you win and lose half the time,
you're right down the middle. you should
technically be break even. Wrong because
I have a positive risk-to-reward ratio.
Let me break this down on this side
right here. So, we know no entry, no
confirmation, right? So, let's say out
of 10 positions, right? So, we're going
to have one 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10. Now we
have one L, 2 L, 3 L, 4 L, 5 L's, and
then we have one W, two W's, three W's,
four W's, 5 [music] W's. Now, this is at
a 50% win rate. Now, meaning if I were
to lose, I would lose -1, -1, -1, -1,
minus one. Whenever I'd win, it'd be
plus two plus two plus two plus two plus
two because I have a one to2
risk-to-reward. So with the first three
wins,
I am already up 6%. So I've already made
back all of my five losses and I'm
technically plus one. So these other 4%
that I'm up, we add it to the four
kindergarten math. I'm technically up
five. So, I am winning and losing
literally the exact same amount of
times, but I win more than I lose
because I have a positive
risk-to-reward. Obviously, the larger
you put this number, if you put this at
a 1 to three, put it at a 1 to four, the
much more profitable you will be. You
don't need to win more amount of times.
you can actually have a 30% win rate and
still be more profitable than 90% of the
people because you have a very large
risk-to-reward. Let me show you what
that looks like. Let's say, for example,
if you were to have a 30% win rate,
which is quite common in this industry,
right? We'll do the same example.
[music] 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10. Let's say
you were to only win three positions. WW
ww and then every position is an L and
it doesn't matter what order this comes
in. So you have a 30% win rate but you
always have a minimum of a 1 to4
risk-to-reward. So meaning whenever you
win you win four times what you
originally risk. So this would be +4 + 4
+ 4 and all this would be -1 -1 -1 -1 -1
-1 -1. So this would be technically all
this combined would be min - 7
with two of these positions.
We're already plus eight. So we already
[music] offset this pos1 plus the four.
Same exact kindergarten math. We are up
5%.
by literally winning 30% of the time.
You're going to tell me with all of this
information that I just educated you
right now, you can't win 30% of the
time. It's quite impossible if you
can't, right? But what you need to do is
set your stop loss and your takerit
correctly so you can have these one to
four risk-to-rewards. Now, we know that
the stop loss to be placed below the
area of interest. Our takerit needs to
be placed at the nearest structure
point. So, I'm going to write this down
for you.
Now, what does that mean?
>> So, I'm guessing uh the one is the red
and then the three would be
>> correct. Correct. So, the yes, the this
this would be the one right here would
be in the red and then the three would
be up here or two or four or five or
whatever, but at a minimum always a two.
That's what your risk-to-reward needs to
be like. But when it comes to
take-profit placement,
take profit
placement
need to place it
at the nearest
structure point.
What does that mean? The nearest
structure point, think about it almost
as the next checkpoint. So, you know
when you would play I think it was
Pac-Man, not sure what game it was, but
it was one of these games when you would
get to the checkpoint and you're trying
to get to the next point. If you fall,
you always get back to that last
checkpoint.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Like the flag.
>> That would be the flag. Correct. That's
exactly what the next structure point
is. It's that checkpoint. It's the the
next point where you can be your safe
area. So, the next checkpoint, the next
structure point is literally the last
area that the market has reacted from.
So clearly before all of this even
happened, the market came into this area
with a bullish momentum and then we
slowed down here for whatever example
and then we started having this
retracement to continue to go to the
upside. So we always need to anticipate
that the market could make it into this
area again, right? So we can make it
into this area, but then we can also
reject this area how it has just done in
the past literally and it can have the
move back to the downside. So, you
always need to place your takerit at the
nearest structure point where the market
could have a reaction from exactly how
it's done to the past. Does that make
sense?
>> Yes, sir. Quick question. What time
frame is this on?
>> This could be on any time frame. So, it
really just comes down to obviously the
overall direction of the trade. Are you
trading with the higher time frames,
lower time frames? But typically for
stop-loss placements, and this is a
little bit of a of a hack right here.
So, it's like a little side note,
stop-loss placement,
I always love placing on the 4 hour. And
then for my takerit [music] placements,
I always love placing
on the daily
typically, but depends where you have
the area [music] of interest. If your
area of interest is on the daily, try
and have a daily stop-loss. Try and have
a daily takerit. You know, this is where
you tweak the rules up and down and
everything gets adjusted. And this is
where you perfect and define that win
rate. All of this customization when it
comes to the entry signal, what entry
signal do you have? Do you [music] enter
off of the first one or the second one?
All of this is where it starts affecting
your win rate. You win more, do you lose
more? It all depends to the type of
quality of the position that you
actually take.
>> So, any questions at this point?
>> No, sir.
>> You sure?
>> Yeah. So at this point you really have
the three essential steps that took me
to becoming a profitable trader. You
will be surprised. Dude, you have no
idea how many YouTube videos I had to
see to figure this out. Like what I have
just shared with you in this hour, 2
hour session, whatever took me two years
to understand. I was just watching every
possible video on YouTube and
understanding every possible concept,
every confirm, everything to just end up
having to test everything and see what
works from what didn't. I'm literally
giving you what works directly. I'm
saving you so much time, right? So, I
want to give you a quick recap at this
point right now because I know there's a
lot of information and you're going to
get back to watch this video, but it's
very key that you understand everything
from top down. First things first, we
know topdown
analysis.
This will do two things. It will let us
know do we want to buy the position or
do we want to sell the position. It will
eliminate one or the other option for
us. Makes our job a lot easier. Step two
is area of interest. Where do we enter
that position that we're looking to buy
or to sell? There's so much information
on the chart. We need a key point. Area
of interest will give us that. And then
third step which is the last and quite
the most important step is where you
actually start to trade is your entry
signal. What is the reason you're going
to enter this position? And you can only
do this when you are inside of the area
of interest. You can have your engulfing
candlesticks get [music] formed. You can
have your dogee candlesticks get formed,
but you always want to enter off of a
confirmation candlestick closure, not an
anticipation. Key takeaways is stop-loss
placements always place at an area. If
hit
you are
what?
>> Going to
>> fully wrong. Correct. And then your
takerit is what?
>> For the win. No, the No, say the flag.
The checkpoint.
>> Oh, the checkpoint. Okay.
>> And take profit is what?
>> The flag. The checkpoint.
>> Correct. The next
structure point that the market could
have a reaction from. You have
everything you need in order for you to
have a winning position. That's all you
need. Now, if you guys enjoy this video,
not only do you guys hit that like and
thumbs up button, but I educate traders
like this every single week in real
time. I give them my top markets that
I'm interested in trading for the week.
I share with them where I'm looking to
enter the position, what entry signal
can we have for that specific trade.
Will it be a swing trade, a day trade? I
break down every single Sunday with my
students what exact markets I'm
interested in trading. And I review the
trade setups to make sure that what
they're doing is correct and incorrect.
Very similar to what I'm doing with
Harley right now. If you guys want to
know more information about that, hit
the link in description below, watch the
video so you guys can actually
understand more in depth of what my
strategy consists of. Aside from that,
if you guys enjoy this video, hit that
like and thumbs up button. We have many
other videos like this education [music]
on the channel. I hope you guys enjoyed
this video and watch all the way to the
end. Make sure you go back, watch this
recording, write down notes because this
is exactly what I did that took me to
becoming a profitable trader back in my
2021 2020 days. So, hope you guys
enjoyed this video. Hit that thumbs up
and I'll see you guys in the next video.